<Document>
# Departmental Security SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Departmental Security[/bold][/color] of this station.


<ColorBox>
  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Center" Margin="10">
    [color=#1b67a5][bold]Departmental Security[/bold][/color] are departmentalized light security officers, meant to protect their department head and departmental assets due to rising crime rates.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>


The list of departmental security jobs is as follows: Medical Orderlies, Cargo Insurance, Sci-Curity Guards, and Engineering Sentries.


1. Though by technicality a member of the security department, departmental security guards are NOT security officers. Thusly, they are generally not allowed to hold firearms, sentence detainees, or generally act AS security.
<Box>Departmental security may still be deputized or entrusted with security weaponry as with any other crew member, and in fact it is encouraged as they are trusted, mindshielded NT hires. </Box>


2. As far as security duties are concerned, departmental security guards are obligated only to OBSERVE AND REPORT on their security radios and report papers, but are encouraged to use their equipment and status to perform a citizen's arrest and detain anyone harming/thieving from the departmental guard's individual department.


3. Departmental security is to secure their department as is best to prevent theft and workplace violence before performing any other departmental functions.
<Box>Ensure every sensitive departmental item is properly stored in access locked lockers or rooms, wrench down said lockers, deliver speeches about relevant inappropriate workplace conduct to department employees, whatever can be done to ensure a safe and secure workplace</Box>


4. Departmental security is to protect their department head as their primary objective. The departmental guard may choose to guard their department or follow the department head should they leave their department, whatever is best for departmental security.


5. Departmental security is NOT to overtake the duties of their department without the consent of the parties involved. Exceptions apply when no one else is healthy enough to perform these duties, and when severe incompetence has been displayed. E.G standing around with dead patients, failure to set up power.

</Document>
